yeah
うん
so
それで
withdrawal
撤退
In Januarylene felon.
ジャニュアレン重罪犯。
An
アン
Professor Chen, Dear Returnees, Dear Colleagues
チェン教授、帰国者の皆様、同僚の皆様
Welcome to today's feast of knowledge
今日の知識の饗宴へようこそ
The speaker we invited today is Professor Chen Dongsen from the Department of Sociology, National Taiwan University
本日お招きした講演者は、国立台湾大学社会学部の陳東森教授です。
Professor Chen Dongsen is a Bachelor of Public Health Department of National Taiwan University School of Medicine
チェン・ドンセン教授は国立台湾大学医学部公衆衛生学科の学士です。
Later, I changed my plan and returned to the United States to study a doctorate in sociology.
その後、私は計画を変更し、社会学の博士号を学ぶために米国に戻りました。
These two are very different
この2つは大きく異なります
Then he returned to National Taiwan University as an associate professor in the Department of Sociology
その後、国立台湾大学社会学部の准教授として戻りました。
department head
部長
When I met him, he was the head of the Department of Sociology
私が彼に会ったとき、彼は社会学部の部長でした。
At that time, the Humanities Department of the National Science Council organized a humanities and social sciences camp for high school students.
当時、全米科学会議の人文科学部は高校生を対象とした人文社会科学キャンプを企画した。
The camp director is Professor Chen Dongsen
キャンプ所長は陳東森教授
I also noticed a few people today
今日も何人かの人がいたことに気づきました
students graduating students
卒業生
also here
ここもまた
Then he was in 2005 to 2007
それから彼は2005年から2007年まで
Served as Director of Humanities and Social Sciences Division of National Science Council
米国科学会議の人文社会科学部門局長を歴任
During his tenure, he has done many meaningful and remarkable things.
在職中、彼は多くの有意義で注目すべきことを行ってきました。
He also served as the editor-in-chief of Taiwan Sociology
『台湾社会学』編集長も務めた
Served as a knowledge committee member of the Institute of Chinese and Foreign Studies
中国外国語学院知識委員会委員を務める
He is also the chairman of the Taiwan Sociological Association
彼は台湾社会学会の会長でもあります。
He has written a lot and has won many honors, including being the research director of the Chinese Academy of Sciences.
彼は多くの著作を執筆しており、国立科学研究所の所長を含む多くの栄誉を獲得しています。
One of the topics he's going to talk about today is quite theoretical.
彼が今日話そうとしているトピックの 1 つは、非常に理論的なものです。
I am very pleased that so many people come with such a topic
このような話題にたくさんの人が来てくれてとても嬉しいです
I am very happy for Professor Chen
チェン教授にとても感謝しています
This is a highly theoretical topic
これは非常に理論的なトピックです
Compared to our previous topic
前回のトピックと比較して
So today's topic is self-reliance and social cooperation
さて、今日のテーマは自立と社会協力です。
On the surface, these two topics seem to be
表面的には、これら 2 つのトピックは次のように見えます。
There is Middle-earth, but in fact it has a very complicated relationship
中つ国はありますが、実際には非常に複雑な関係があります
Both Chinese and Western thought are discussing this issue
中国と西洋の両方の思想がこの問題を議論している
I'm personally very interested in this question too
私も個人的にこの質問に非常に興味があります
So we now welcome Professor Chen with warm applause
それでは、温かい拍手をもってチェン教授をお迎えいたします。
Vice President Wang and everyone here
王副総統とここにいる皆さん
It's very unexpected to come here to speak today.
今日ここに来て講演することは非常に予想外でした。
Because just now Vice President Wang introduced me to serve in the National Science Council
なぜなら、たった今、王副主席が私に国家学術会議の委員を紹介してくれたからです。
In fact, I am in the National Science Council
実際、私は米国科学会議の会員です
In fact, during the service period, it was mainly due to the strong support of Vice President Wang.
在任期間中、これは主に王副総統の強力な支援によるものでした。
So he wants me to come, I dare not not come
だから彼は私に来て欲しいのですが、私はあえて来ません
Although I personally feel that this speech is really heavy for me.
私自身、このスピーチは本当に重いと感じていますが。
So the outline of the speech prepared by the speech was changed again
そこで、スピーチで用意されたスピーチの概要が再び変更されました
These days are changing
最近は変わりつつあります
So it's a thankless task, but it doesn't seem like there's much choice
それはありがたい仕事ですが、あまり選択肢はないようです
So I'll try to share what I know with you.
そこで、私が知っていることを皆さんと共有しようと思います。
Well, today's topic was just said by Vice President Wang to be very theoretical.
さて、今日のテーマは、先ほど王副総統が非常に理論的なことをおっしゃいました。
Then I hope that what I can discuss with you is relatively simple.
それでは、比較的簡単な内容でお話しできればと思います。
I think maybe everyone can do more or less
おそらく誰でも多かれ少なかれできることだと思います
can also understand
も理解できます
That's because the subject of this study
それはこの研究の主題だからです
The sociology I learned by myself
独学で学んだ社会学
The relationship can be said to be quite close
かなり親密な関係と言えるでしょう
Most people may not know
おそらくほとんどの人は知らないでしょう
What is Sociology about?
社会学とは何ですか?
I always feel that studying sociology is very good at understanding society
社会学を学ぶことは社会を理解するのに非常に優れているといつも感じています
Then you look like I don't understand society
そうすると君は社会を理解していないように見える
doesn't look alike
似てない
So if you study sociology, you don't understand society
だから社会学を勉強しても社会は分からない
Sometimes relationships don't have to be that way
時には人間関係は必ずしもそうである必要はない
so direct
とても直接的
Well, many of our students have studied sociology
さて、私たちの学生の多くは社会学も学んでいます
then two
それから2つ
after a year
1年後
They don't know whether they know sociology in the end
結局彼らは社会学を知っているかどうかも知らない
what are you studying
何を勉強しているの
Then I'm talking about this Chile working with this society
それから私はこの社会と協力するこのチリについて話しているのです
actually
実際
there's another one there
そこにもう一つあります
actually want to express
実際に表現したい
one thing to show
見せるものは一つ
that is
あれは
We are in sociology or economics and political science
私たちは社会学、経済学、政治学を専攻しています
The topic being discussed is nothing more than
議論されている話題はそれ以外の何ものでもありません
relationship between people
人と人との関係
I would look at it like this
私はそれをこのように見ます
Emphasis in economics on the competition of such markets
経済学ではそのような市場の競争が重視される
Emphasize that people start from a more independent perspective
人々はより独立した視点から始めることを強調する
with sociology
社会学と
sociology is not about
社会学は問題ではありません
There will be no competition between people
人々の間で競争がなくなる
Maybe the one he pays more attention to
たぶん彼がもっと注意を払っているのは
relationship with people
人との関係
under a team of reciprocal and trusting cooperation
相互信頼できる協力チームの下で
to carry out
実行する
So what we are more familiar with is
ですから、私たちがもっとよく知っているのは、
The way this market works
この市場の仕組み
Of course competition has become what we are used to
もちろん、競争は私たちが慣れ親しんだものになっています
But we may often forget to say
しかし、私たちはよく言うことを忘れてしまうかもしれません
There are still many times between people
人と人との間にはまだたくさんの時間があります
It is possible only through cooperation
協力があってこそ可能になる
So I'm going to just put this
だからこれだけ載せておきます
Sociology Emphasis in Research
研究における社会学重視
It's talking about reciprocity and cooperation
それは互恵性と協力です
that economics
その経済学
Let's take it more like we're talking about this competition
このコンテストについて話しているように考えましょう
Then our small examination institute sales talk about political science
それから私たちの小さな試験機関のセールストークは政治学についてです
Political thought is also broad spirit
政治思想も広い精神
Then what I want to talk about is the distribution of power
そこで私が話したいのは権力の配分についてです
So under a power structure
つまり権力構造の下では
Probably because of this kind of subordinate relationship
こういう従属関係だからだろう
So what is the relationship between these three different people?
では、この異なる3人の関係はどのようなものなのでしょうか？
I think it is the aspect that these three disciplines may attach importance to
この3つの分野が重要視する可能性がある側面だと思います
not the same
不太一樣
So I will talk about this Chile working with this society
そこで私はこの社会と協力するチリについて話します
Of course, I am also trying to solve some very fundamental problems.
もちろん、いくつかの非常に根本的な問題も解決しようとしています。
Then I don't think it's easy for me to make a fuss
そうすれば大騒ぎするのは簡単ではないと思います
But in the seventeenth century the philosopher Hobbes
しかし、17世紀に哲学者ホッブズは、
This Vavius ​​he wrote is this spiritism
彼が書いたこのバビウスはこの心霊術です
In fact, he has clearly mentioned
実際、彼ははっきりと述べています
It's just that people are Chilean selfish
チリ人は利己的だというだけだ
I put selfishness with chile and i don't put him off for now
私はチリに利己主義を課し、今のところ彼を無視しません
He makes a very clear distinction just for himself
彼は自分自身のためだけに非常に明確な区別をしています
for yourself you have to survive
自分自身のために、生き残らなければなりません
In the discussion of Hobbes
ホッブズの議論の中で
People follow each other in order to maintain their own survival
人は自らの生存を維持するために互いにフォローし合う
this endless war
この終わりのない戦争
what do you want peace
何を平和に望んでいますか
People can only cede power to this country
人々はこの国に権力を譲渡することしかできない
Govern by the state to maintain an order
国家が秩序を維持するために統治する
make these chileans
これらのチリ人を作ります
He was able to be in a relatively peaceful state like this
このように比較的平穏な状態でいることができました
Come spend a day like ours
私たちのような一日を過ごしましょう
full of order full of stability
秩序に満ちた安定感に満ちた
this way of life
この生き方
Hobbes' view
ホッブズの見解
Of course it represents
もちろんそれは表しています
is why the country exists
それが国が存在する理由です
Why do countries exist
なぜ国が存在するのか
very important reason
非常に重要な理由
But I think it might be a pity
でもそれは残念かもしれないと思う
Hobbes if he looked further ahead
ホッブスがもっと先を見据えていたら
From looking at it is the development of human society
見てみると人間社会の発展です
this origin of history
この歴史の起源
before there was no country
国がなくなる前に
In fact, many of these primitive societies
実際、これらの原始社会の多くは、
Anthropological research clearly shows that
人類学の研究は明らかに次のことを示しています
Actually it's not in Infinity War
実はインフィニティ・ウォーには無いんです
They can keep the peace in a variety of ways
彼らはさまざまな方法で平和を維持できる
One of the most important is the exchange of physical
最も重要なことの 1 つは物理的な交換です。
Anthropologists
人類学者
A famous anthropologist named Marsha Schellings
マーシャ・シェリングスという有名な人類学者
He mentioned in the study of the original society that
彼は原初の社会の研究で次のように述べました。
The origin of physical exchange is actually
物理的な交換の起源は実は
You are in a situation where everyone is working hard
みんなが頑張っている状況です
How do you avoid endless war
終わりのない戦争をどうやって避けるか
The best thing to do is lay down your weapons
一番良いのは武器を捨てることだ
Give the other person a gift to show your kindness
あなたの優しさを伝えるために相手に贈り物をしましょう
If the other party stands at this reciprocal angle
相手がこの逆角度に立っていれば
He also answered your words of a gift
彼はあなたの贈り物の言葉にも答えました
Ongoing exchange of such gifts
このような贈り物の交換は継続的に行われます
Only peace can continue to operate
平和だけが継続できる
i talk about hobbes
ホッブスについて話します
tell this anthropologist
この人類学者に言ってください
Actually what I want to mention is that
実は私が言いたいのは、
even at the beginning
最初でも
he may survive
彼は生き残るかもしれない
For the reproduction of the race
レースの再現に向けて
he may be self-reliant
彼は自立しているかもしれない
may be selfish
利己的かもしれない
After all, there is some mechanism
やっぱり何らかの仕組みがあるんだね
There are ways to make that cooperation
その協力を実現する方法はあります
He can develop gradually
彼は徐々に成長できる
That's the foreword
それが序文です
Talk a little bit about the previous one
前回のことを少し話しましょう
one origin one history
一個原起一個歷史
Then if we go back to comparing
それでは比較に戻ってみると
This discussion in modern times
現代におけるこの議論
that was in 1968
それは1968年のことでした
this is an economist
これは経済学者です
I don't know much about economics
経済のことはあまり詳しくないのですが、
But this economist
しかし、この経済学者は、
1968 The Harding
1968年 ハーディング
he in this one
この中の彼
This publication is very important in academia
この出版物は学術界で非常に重要です
Science1968
Science 1968年
He brought up this tragedy about public wealth
彼は公共の富に関するこの悲劇を持ち出した
an argument like this
このような議論
If people are independent
人が自立すれば
that no one would do for public affairs
公務では誰もやらないだろう
any effort for the public good
公共の利益のためのあらゆる努力
Because this public property means
なぜなら、この公共財産というのは、
as long as others do
他の人がそうする限り
then you can enjoy
そうすれば楽しむことができます
Someone else cleaned up the park
他の人が公園を掃除した
then you can enjoy a clean
そうすれば、きれいな状態を楽しむことができます
beautiful this park
美しいこの公園
then you can't
それならできません
if you are intellectual
あなたが知的であれば
then why are you paying
ではなぜお金を払っているのか
The house has been cleaned
家は掃除されました
then you don't do anything
それならあなたは何もしません
you can do it and enjoy it
あなたはそれをやって楽しむことができます
For those who are intelligent
知的な人にとっては
must be hitchhikers
ヒッチハイカーに違いない
So from this Harding
それで、このハーディングから
present this tragedy of the commons
このコモンズの悲劇を提示する
after
後
Later there was a lot of this debate
その後、この議論がたくさんありました
that is
あれは
if everyone is intelligent
誰もが知的であれば
How about this kind of public affairs?
こういう広報はどうですか？
then
それから
probably only two options
おそらく選択肢は2つだけ
One is to find out the country again
一つはその国をもう一度知ることです
find the country again
もう一度国を見つけてください
That is when we also often refer to
そのときに私たちがよく言及するのは、
If public facilities related to public interest
公益に関わる公共施設の場合
tax increase by the state
州による増税
to provide
提供する
Lest everyone is unwilling to pay
みんなが支払いたくないことのないように
or unwilling to do something
または何かをしたくない
Or donate a little more to provide this public facility
あるいは、この公共施設を提供するためにもう少し寄付してください
by the state
州によって
may be a good way
良い方法かもしれない
The other is to let the market
もう一つは市場に任せることです
Turn this public thing into privatization
この公共のものを民営化する
everyone you want to use
使いたい人全員
If you can define private property
プライベートプロパティを定義できれば
After you define this clearly
これを明確に定義した後、
You treat everyone who wants to use him as property
あなたは彼を利用したい人全員を所有物のように扱います
to use
使用する
you know you have to pay the price
代償を支払わなければならないことはわかっています
Of course we also know that there are many things
もちろん、いろいろあることも承知しています
He has no way to treat it as a private property
彼にはそれを私有地として扱う方法がない
Like the air or the ocean
空気や海のように
you can't define
定義することはできません
So Harding mentions the tragedy of the commons
そこでハーディングはコモンズの悲劇について言及する
in 1968
1968年に
options he could discuss at that time
その時点で彼が話し合える選択肢
Probably the market and the country
おそらく市場と国
But after Harding
しかしハーディングの後
There is probably an important
おそらく重要なことがあります
The political economist is this OSShuang
政治経済学者はこのOSShuangです
This is the winner of the 2009 Nobel Prize in Economics
この人は2009年のノーベル経済学賞受賞者です
the lady
女性
she is a public economist
彼女は公共経済学者です
a political scientist
政治学者
Then her most important work in 1995
そして1995年の彼女の最も重要な作品
public resource governance
公共リソースのガバナンス
Or in the book on the governance of public property
あるいは公共財産のガバナンスに関する本でも
She clearly mentioned that
彼女ははっきりとそう言った
There are not only two options, the country and the market
選択肢は国と市場の2つだけではない
In fact, there are other possibilities
実は他にも可能性はある
There is another possibility
別の可能性もあります
So she spent a lot of space in this book
それで彼女はこの本の中で多くのスペースを費やしました
Criticizing and discussing why the market
なぜ市場なのかを批判し議論する
Why the state is not necessarily more effective than anything
なぜ国家が何よりも効果的であるとは限らないのか
than the average public
平均的な一般人よりも
Discuss by yourself
自分で話し合ってください
Self-discussion means what kind of norms we want to set
自己議論とは、どのような規範を設定したいのかを意味します
Then how do we make this public resource
では、このリソースを公開するにはどうすればよいでしょうか
That's called maintaining together
それは一緒に維持するというものです
This is actually possible
これは実際に可能です
Then this post by Oshuang
それからOshuangさんのこの投稿
In fact, very attentive
実際、とても気配りがあって、
He spent about thirty years
彼は約３０年を費やした
There are about 3,000 collected around the world
世界中で約3,000点が収集されている
about the use of public resources
公共リソースの利用について
So these 3,000 examples are from about hundreds of years ago
つまり、これらの 3,000 の例は約数百年前のものです
in the mountains of switzerland
スイスの山の中で
forest in japan
日本の森
this ranch in switzerland
スイスのこの牧場
to this modern
この現代に
his own doctoral dissertation
彼自身の博士論文
He is studying this Los Angeles
彼はこのロサンゼルスで勉強しています
This throughout the Los Angeles area
これはロサンゼルス全域で
use of groundwater
地下水の利用
he established a center
彼はセンターを設立した
those thirty years
その30年間
Just keep collecting all kinds of cases
あらゆる種類のケースを集め続けるだけです
watching say
見て言う
Discussed by members of the community themselves
コミュニティのメンバー自身による議論
under what circumstances
どのような状況で
will succeed
成功します
What kind of conditions
どのような条件ですか
he is unlikely to succeed
彼は成功しそうにない
The achievements of these thirty years
この30年間の成果
It is very clear in this book that
この本の中ではっきりとわかるのは、
I just said that I avoided being too abstract
抽象的になりすぎることは避けたと言ったばかりです
so i took it in the book
それで本に取り入れました
in its works
その作品の中で
The example where it's often mentioned
よく言われる例としては
this one in Türkiye
これはトゥルキエにあります
This fishing village in Alunya is probably at this location
アルーニャのこの漁村はおそらくこの場所にあります
in the mediterranean at this location
地中海のこの場所で
Everyone has a little bit of this concept on the map
誰もがこの概念を地図上に少しずつ持っています
Enough
十分
If you have this iPhone you can take it out and locate it
この iPhone をお持ちであれば、取り出して見つけることができます
see where it is
どこにあるか見てください
how far is it from us
私たちからどれくらい離れていますか
this alanya this place
このアラニヤ、この場所
Some field research done by Oswang himself
オワング自身が行ったフィールド調査
This fishing village has about 100 people
この漁村には人口が100人ほどいます
There are 100 people
100人います
It is a local cooperative that produces
を生産している地元の協同組合です。
But in the 1970s
しかし1970年代には
because of this market
この市場のせいで
Also, the fishermen want to increase their income
また、漁師たちは収入を増やしたいと考えています。
So a lot to catch this catch
この獲物を捕まえるのはとてもたくさんです
There is no limit to the amount of catch
捕獲量に制限はありません
In order to snatch better fishing spots
より良い釣り場を掴むために
so there's a lot of conflict
だからたくさんの衝突がある
a lot of conflict
たくさんの衝突
And more importantly because you keep replenishing
そしてさらに重要なのは、補充し続けるためです
There is no way for everyone in this fishing group to reply within a period of time
この釣りグループの全員が一定期間内に返信する方法はありません
So you heal and you become smaller
それであなたは治って小さくなります
Then this amount is less and less
そうなるとサプリメントの数はどんどん減っていきます
The fishing time is getting longer and longer
釣り時間がどんどん長くなっていきます
So it's hard for everyone to live
だからみんな生きづらいんだよ
So in this 1970s with such a big problem
このような大きな問題を抱えたこの 1970 年代に
Then this fishery is of course a public resource
そうすると、この漁業は当然公共資源です。
is owned by everyone
全員が所有している
then what should we do
じゃあどうすればいいのか
If everyone goes to make up for it
みんなが埋め合わせに行ったら
Make it up in small fishing
小さな釣りでそれを補う
Then do this like this
次に、これを次のようにします
you can't get any catch
何も捕まえることはできません
that's in alanya
それはアラニヤにあります
These 100 fishermen want to say the question goes on like this
この 100 人の漁師は、問題は次のように続くと言いたいのです。
is unsolvable
解決不可能です
Then everyone may starve to death
そうなるとみんな餓死するかもしれない
so what about them
それで彼らはどうですか
They because we just mentioned
先ほど触れたばかりなので、
They have a co-op here that produces this
ここに協同組合があり、これを生産しています
So they decided to say
そこで彼らはこう言うことにした
This member in this production cooperative
この生産組合のこの組合員は
Let's find this local resident
この地元住民を見つけよう
let's discuss
話し合いましょう
Let's see how to solve such a problem
このような問題を解決する方法を見てみましょう
so they made some effort
それで彼らはある程度の努力をした
They put this in this fish factory where they fish
彼らはこれをこの水産工場に置き、そこで漁業を行っています
Because more than 100 people they probably
おそらく100人以上いるので、
two people have a fish boat
二人は漁船を持っています
There are about 50 of these fishing boats
この漁船は約50隻あります
What about the more than 100 people?
100人以上の人はどうなるの？
he put this fish factory
彼はこの魚工場を建てました
Because it is the fishing factory in the offshore
沖合の水産工場なので
They split it into about 50 different locations
彼らはそれを約50の異なる場所に分割しました
50 different locations
50の異なる場所
in this position
この位置で
By way of lottery
抽選により
decide who is in which fishery
誰がどの漁業に所属するかを決める
to go fishing
釣りに行くこと
But the location of the fishery where the fish are caught every day
しかし、毎日魚が獲れる漁場の場所
is moving every day
毎日動いています
September of the current year to January of the following year
その年の9月から翌年の1月まで
the fisherman moved west
漁師は西に引っ越した
Move one fishing ground west
漁場を一つ西に移動
Then from January to May of the following year
その後翌年の1月から5月まで
He moved from west to east again
彼は再び西から東へ移動した
like this
このような
everyone has a chance
誰にでもチャンスがある
in the most fished fishing grounds
最も釣れる漁場で
to go fishing
釣りに行くこと
I describe here
ここで説明します
looks very simple
とてもシンプルに見えます
but what is the important thing
しかし重要なことは何ですか
these fishermen
この漁師たち
They are willing to put their local fishing experience
彼らは地元での釣り体験を喜んで活用します
The information fully shares it out
情報は徹底的に共有します
Otherwise you're cutting up the fishery
さもなければ漁業を解体することになる
to this fishing
この釣りに
with this reflux of his
彼のこの逆流で
Or the one he passed by
あるいは彼が通り過ぎた人
The state of the fish factory
水産工場の様子
it must be fully understood
それは完全に理解されなければなりません
So they cut the fish factory in fact
それで彼らは実際に水産工場を廃止した
Not so ideal when starting to cut
カットを開始するときはあまり理想的ではありません
It's been almost two years
ほぼ2年が経ちました
There is a way to clearly distinguish
明確に見分ける方法があります
the location of those fish factories
それらの魚工場の場所
Then the way the fish factory distributes like this
では、水産工場ではこのように流通しているのです。
So there's this mutual trust
つまり相互の信頼関係があるのです
willing to provide information
情報を提供する意欲がある
In fact, this is a very important
実は、これはとても重要なことなのですが、
very important basis
非常に重要な基礎
Of course this Oshon is not so romantic
もちろん、このオションはそれほどロマンチックではありません
That is, we all trust each other
つまり、私たちは皆、お互いを信頼し合っているのです
management of public resources
公共資源の管理
follow pay
フォローペイ
Everyone will abide by the rules like that
そんなルールならみんな守るよ
incomplete
不完全
He went on to mention
彼は続けて言及した
In the governance of this public resource
この公共リソースのガバナンスにおいて
Discuss a set of rules from bottom to top
一連のルールについて下から上へ話し合う
Discuss a set of norms
一連の規範について話し合う
the rules of the game
ゲームのルール
then he must
それなら彼はそうしなければならない
supervised mechanism
監視されたメカニズム
But the lower the cost of the monitoring mechanism, the better
しかし、監視メカニズムのコストは低ければ低いほど、より良いものになります。
So these 50 fisheries are open seas
つまり、これら 50 の漁業は外洋です
One by one
一個接一個
So if you draw fish or the richest fishery
つまり、魚や最も豊かな漁業を描くと、
You will definitely be the earliest time you can start fishing
確実に一番早く釣りを始めることができます
you go to the fishing ground
あなたは釣り場に行きます
So if someone goes poaching your designated fishery
したがって、誰かがあなたの指定した漁業を密猟した場合、
if fishing over there
あそこで釣りをするなら
will be caught
捕まるだろう
So the monitoring mechanism
したがって、監視メカニズムは
it's the way that comes with the fish farm cut
それは養殖場のカットに伴う方法です
It sounds very simple when I put it this way
こうやって言うとすごくシンプルに聞こえますが、
But in system design
しかし、システム設計においては、
If your kind of management of public resources
あなたが公共リソースを管理しているのであれば、
You need to design a system that people can use
人々が利用できるシステムを設計する必要がある
And in the process of using
そして使用の途中で
Supervised mods
監視付きMOD
The monitoring mechanism is embedded in it
監視メカニズムが組み込まれています
It's actually very, very difficult
それは実際にはとてもとても難しいことです
after being caught
捕まった後
what to do
何をすべきか
What to do after being caught
捕まった後はどうすればいいのか
Of course this OSWANG must have a punishment mechanism
もちろん、この OSWANG には罰メカニズムが必要です
But his punishment mechanism is very special
しかし、彼の罰のメカニズムは非常に特殊です
He said that his punishment mechanism should have two characteristics
彼は、罰のメカニズムには 2 つの特徴があるべきだと述べた
one is immediate punishment
一つは即時処罰
Second, the punishment should not be too severe
第二に、刑罰は厳しすぎてはなりません
just a light punishment
軽い罰だけ
So if you get caught the first time
だから、初めて捕まった場合は
poaching people in fishing grounds
漁場での密漁
If you fish in a place other than your designated fishing ground
指定された釣り場以外の場所で釣りをした場合
how to deal with it
それにどう対処するか
Probably by the chairman of this cooperative
おそらくこの組合の理事長によるものだと思われる
he is in this village
彼はこの村にいます
that's the place
それが場所です
They are like our small villages in Taiwan
彼らは台湾の小さな村のようなものです
long radio station
長いラジオ局
just announce it on the radio
ラジオで発表するだけ
This so-and-so went fishing today
この人たちは今日釣りに行きました
so say it this way
だからこう言ってください
No money or anything
お金も何もない
Because OSWANG knows one thing very well
OSWANG はあることをよく知っているからです
punishment is of course good
罰はもちろん良い
because we'll talk about that later
それについては後で話しますので
But you have to know that the punishment is too severe
しかし、その罰は厳しすぎることを知っておく必要があります
Those who are punished will turn their faces
罰せられた者は顔を背けるだろう
he will take revenge
彼は復讐するだろう
So this will make this penalty
それでこのペナルティが課せられます
the possible effect of
考えられる影響
is relatively limited
比較的限られている
We can continue with everyone later
後でみんなで続けましょう
discuss this issue
この問題について話し合う
then i just mentioned this
それから私はこれについて言及しました
In fact, it is simply to put this OSWANG
実際、これを単純に言うと、OSWANG
its 30 years
30年
The result of this research
この研究の結果
Summed up about eight
8つくらいまとめると
This approach to public governance
公共ガバナンスに対するこのアプローチ
From the bottom up to the community
ボトムアップからコミュニティへ
Eight Basic Principles of Planning in Four Episodes
企画の 8 つの基本原則を 4 つのエピソードで解説
doesn't look like much
あまり似ていません
This knowledge is in fact
この知識は実は
if you think about it
考えてみれば
This content is very very exciting
この内容はとてもとても刺激的です
wonderful enough to get this
これを手に入れるのに十分素晴らしい
Nobio speaks
ノビオが話す
So OSWANG
ソー・オズワン
He said to crack this
彼はこれを解読すると言った
This tragedy of public wealth
国民の富のこの悲劇
between members
メンバー間で
He must be able to communicate
彼は意思疎通ができるに違いない
Because we just mentioned this cut of this fish farm
なぜなら、私たちはこの養殖場のこのカットについて言及したばかりだからです
He needs to communicate with each other
彼はお互いにコミュニケーションを取る必要がある
on this possibility
この可能性について
And he also has some
そして彼もいくつか持っています
So build members of this community
このコミュニティのメンバーを増やしてください
mechanism of mutual trust
相互信頼の仕組み
So you're going to be reciprocal
だからあなたは互恵的になるでしょう
we must work together
私たちは協力しなければなりません
There is no way to avoid this trust
この信頼を避ける方法はありません
Of course we also know
もちろん私たちも知っています
operating in a market
市場で活動している
In fact, he must also have a trust mechanism
実際、信頼メカニズムも必要です
no mechanism for trust
信頼のメカニズムがない
The market can't work either
市場も機能しない
It is impossible for the state to function
国家が機能するのは不可能だ
So this mechanism of trust
つまり、この信頼のメカニズムは、
is very important
はとても重要です
have to communicate
コミュニケーションをとらなければならない
There must be a mechanism for trust
信頼のためのメカニズムが必要です
Where does this trust mechanism come from?
この信頼メカニズムはどこから来たのでしょうか?
because they are a small village
彼らは小さな村なので
they used to have this cooperative
彼らはかつてこの協同組合を持っていました
so there may be some
だからいくつかあるかもしれない
can trust each other
お互いを信頼できる
or
また
There may be some kinship among them
彼らの間には何らかの血縁関係があるかもしれない
Possibility to build trust
信頼関係を築く可能性
Of course they also have to understand
もちろん彼らも理解しなければなりません
Because of their shared use of resources
リソースを共有して使用するため
less and less catches
漁獲量がどんどん減っていきます
Everyone spends more and more time fishing
誰もが釣りに費やす時間がますます増えています
lower and lower income
収入はどんどん減っていきます
that common fate
その共通の運命
so that everyone should be able to clearly understand
誰もが明確に理解できるように
Then Ostron also mentioned that
それからオストロンもこう言いました
The country's public resources on this entire Youschool.com
この国の公共リソースは Youschool.com 全体にあります
mechanism of self-governance
自治の仕組み
The best thing to do is not to give too much of this intervention
最善のことは、この介入をあまり与えないことです
Provide this local community opportunity
地域コミュニティにこの機会を提供する
give this opportunity and time
この機会と時間を与えてください
Let this public of this community develop their own
このコミュニティの一般の人々に独自の開発をしてもらいましょう
This specification governing this common resource
この共通リソースを管理するこの仕様
In fact, he still has many very exciting discussions.
実際、彼は今でも非常に刺激的な議論をたくさんしています。
very very wonderful discussion
とてもとても素晴らしい議論
Including that if your country really wants to manage
あなたの国が本当に管理したい場合はそれも含めて
Then you have to make sure your information is not enough
次に、自分の情報が十分でないことを確認する必要があります
you want to make sure you punish
確実に罰したいのですか
Are you punishing the right person?
あなたは正しい人を罰していますか？
this is very important
これはとても重要です
because you punished the wrong person
あなたは間違った人を罰したからです
will lead to more opportunism
さらなるご都合主義につながるだろう
He can even figure it out
彼はそれを理解することさえできる
If someone breaks the law today
今日誰かが法律を破ったら
you can't help
あなたは助けることができません
Immediate and correct penalty over 75%
75% を超える即時かつ適切なペナルティ
State intervention will only lead to more arrests
国家介入は逮捕者を増やすだけだ
More violations of the law
さらなる法律違反
So he once cited in the book
それで彼はかつて本の中で引用しました
Canadian government intervenes with the Eskimos of the North
カナダ政府が北部のエスキモーに介入
Do Catch Control Canada's Fisheries Agency Gets Involved
カナダ水産庁が関与する「Do Catch Control」
The result is a mess
結果はめちゃくちゃです
So he is in this book
それで彼はこの本の中にいます
my personal opinion
私の個人的な意見
I think OSRON is more like a sociologist
オスロンは社会学者に近いと思う
But this is of course our own interpretation and interpretation.
しかし、これはもちろん私たちの独自の解釈と解釈です。
The important thing is that
重要なことは、
Why is he more like a sociologist?
なぜ彼は社会学者に似ているのでしょうか？
He emphasized that this bottom-up
彼はこのボトムアップを強調した。
This kind of communication and discussion
このようなコミュニケーションやディスカッション
short-term intelligence
短期的な知性
Transformed into everyone taking into account the interests of the public
公共の利益を考慮して全員に変身
Finally of course to everyone
最後にもちろん皆さんにも
detached from one's own interests
自分の利益から切り離された
maintenance of long-term interests
長期的な利益の維持
is helpful
役に立ちます
Then this communication and discussion
それからこのコミュニケーションとディスカッション
can let us understand
私たちに理解させてもらえますか
our chile
私たちのチリ
Sometimes it's too short-sighted
時々それは近視眼的すぎる
only focus on the present
現在だけに集中する
How much can I gain today
今日はどれくらい稼げるか
try not to
しないようにしてみてください
catch as much as possible
できるだけ捕まえる
but did not expect
しかし期待していませんでした
possibly to ourselves in the long run
おそらく長期的には私たち自身にとっても
is bad
悪い
But after these discussions
しかし、こうした議論の後、
it is possible for us to understand
私たちには理解することが可能です
The public interest is relatively long-term
公益は比較的長期にわたる
the public interest
公益
how to build it
どのように構築するか
so if we look at
それで見てみると
I turned to public property
公共財産に目を向けました
This kind of discussion of this public resource
このコモンズに関するこの種の議論
we probably
私たちはおそらく
I thought
私は思った
that is
あれは
Are we thinking that people are really that rational?
人間は本当にそこまで合理的だと私たちは考えているのでしょうか？
is when
いつ
You see everyone making up
みんなが仲直りしているのが見える
then you can't help
それならあなたは助けることができません
So you follow suit
だからあなたもそれに倣う
maybe you don't know
たぶんあなたは知りません
you look like
あなたは次のように見えます
you got a lot that day
あなたはその日たくさんのものを手に入れました
But what?
でも何？
half a year later
半年後
you may have no income
収入がないかもしれない
So we say people are so rational
だから人々はとても合理的だと言うのです
If people only pay attention to this kind of short-term benefit
もし人々がこの短期的な利益だけに注目するなら
In fact, the interests of the whole society as a whole
実際、社会全体の利益は
may be harmful
有害かもしれない
Ultimately for the long-term benefit of the individual
最終的には個人の長期的な利益のために
probably not too good
おそらくあまり良くない
so i just said
だから私はちょうど言った
that use of that common resource
その共通リソースの使用
like this public fishing ground
この公営漁場みたいに
this shit
このたわごと
In the long run, there are problems
長期的には問題もある
Then of course we will want to say
それからもちろん、私たちはこう言いたくなります。
that man is so independent
あの人はとても独立心が強い
if people are so self-reliant
人々がそれほど自立しているなら
Then why after communication and discussion
では、コミュニケーションとディスカッションの後、なぜ
Everyone is willing to give up this kind of short-term benefit
誰もがこの種の短期的な利益を喜んで放棄します
that considering the long-term
長期的なことを考えると
This effort may lead to better
この努力がより良いものにつながるかもしれません
The effect of individual and public
個人と公共の効果
That's a few questions I'm thinking about
それが私が考えているいくつかの質問です
So I also want to discuss here
そこで、ここでも議論したいと思います
Does that mean people are that rational?
ということは、人間はそれほど合理的だということなのでしょうか？
When we are talking about man being self-reliant
人間の自立について話しているとき
Of course we would like to say that people want
もちろん、人々は望んでいると言いたいのですが、
able to calculate clearly
明確に計算できる
Estimate how much you will pay
いくら支払うかを見積もる
Then how much can you get
じゃあいくらもらえるの
Is that man so rational?
あの人はそんなに合理的ですか？
that recently
最近のこと
last year
去年
Should be this
これであるべきです
Professor of a business school at Duke University in the United States
米国デューク大学ビジネススクール教授
he wrote a book called
彼はという本を書きました
predictable irrationality
予測可能な不合理
that book is quite interesting
その本はとても面白いです
So I also read from that book
それで私もその本を読みました
Take a few examples
いくつか例を挙げてみましょう
let's discuss
話し合いましょう
Are people that rational?
人はそんなに合理的ですか？
that person is not that rational
あの人はそこまで合理的ではない
what kind of problems will arise
どのような問題が起こるか
we can think again
私たちはもう一度考えることができます
that first example
最初の例
i was going to say
言おうと思ってた
this speech is boring
このスピーチは退屈です
So please come with me on this
それで、私と一緒にこれについて来てください
do some games
いくつかのゲームをする
But because we are now
でも私たちは今だから
Our classmate who took my class already knows
私の授業を受けたクラスメートはすでに知っています
So I dropped the idea
それで私はそのアイデアをやめました
That
それか
What is this example?
この例は何ですか?
That means we now have zero 012 to 100
つまり、012 ～ 100 はゼロになります。
012 to 100
012～100
Then you can try it
それなら試してみてもいいよ
If we want to ask you now
今すぐ聞きたい場合は
Please think of a number
数字を考えてください
you have to think seriously
真剣に考えなければなりません
write a number
数字を書く
That means we're doing everyone writing a number
つまり、全員に数字を書いてもらうということです
but
しかし
our target is
私たちの目標は
you wrote the right number
あなたは正しい番号を書きました
is close to the number written by everyone
みんなが書いた数字に近いです
2/3 of the average
平均の2/3
i say it again
もう一度言います
Everyone understand what I mean
誰もが私の言いたいことを理解しています
We now have this number from 0 to 100
これで、0 から 100 までの数字が得られます。
You can write anywhere from 0 to 100
0から100まで書き込めます
You can write 3 or 5
3つまたは5つを書くことができます
but you have to notice
しかし、あなたは気づかなければなりません
We want you to achieve this
これを達成してほしいと思っています
what is the goal you want to achieve
あなたが達成したい目標は何ですか
you have to guess correctly
正しく推測する必要があります
Each of us fills in this number
私たち一人一人がこの数字を記入します
on average
平均して
then multiply by 3 by 2
次に 3 と 2 を掛けます
the value of
の値
Although this is a small game
これは小さなゲームですが、
But this is often spared
しかし、これはしばしば回避されます
Where is the backup?
バックアップはどこにありますか?
about ten years ago
10年ほど前
There used to be a very boring person
昔、とてもつまらない人がいました
On this plane flying from the UK to the US
イギリスからアメリカまでのこの飛行機で
this light exploded
この光が爆発した
you are bored on the plane
あなたは飛行機で退屈しています
You just give him a list like this
このようなリストを彼に渡すだけです
tell you to write
書くように言ってください
He'll send this list a thousand times
彼はこのリストを何千回も送信するだろう
Then you can write in this grid on the plane
次に、平面上のこのグリッドに書き込むことができます
His bonus is if you guessed right
彼のボーナスはあなたの推測が正しかった場合です
the average
平均
He is giving you one hundred thousand dollars
彼はあなたに10万ドルをあげます
so this is high
だからこれは高いです
very high reward
非常に高い報酬
That's the first example ever brought up
それはこれまでに取り上げられた最初の例です
Then if you look at the online
それでネットを見てみると
the open course
オープンコース
Michael Sandale, who is very popular recently
最近大人気のマイケル・サンダル
speaking about justice
正義について語る
In fact, another very popular one is Yale University.
実際、もう 1 つの非常に人気のある大学はイェール大学です。
There is also a game theory
ゲーム理論もある
game theory
賽局理論
teacher first class
先生のファーストクラス
The homework for the students is this
生徒たちの宿題はこれです
Take out 10 U.S. dollars in class on the spot
授業中にその場で10ドルを引き出す
Say send this list
このリストを送信すると言います
If you write the closest to the average
平均に最も近いものを書くと
2.3 people who write averages per person
1人当たり平均2.3人が書く
Get a $10 bonus
10ドルのボーナスを獲得
There is also a well-known economist
著名な経済学者もいる
at Caltech
カリフォルニア工科大学で
He is also bold
彼は大胆でもある
his board of trustees at caltech
彼はカリフォルニア工科大学の理事です
I also made a game like this
こんなゲームも作りました
I also did it in class
授業でもやりました
our class
私たちのクラス
I'll show you the result
結果を見せます
Our National Taiwan University student
国立台湾大学の学生
This student of National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学の学生です
Everyone fills in this number
全員がこの番号を記入します
We have more than 100 students
私たちには100人以上の生徒がいます
The average is 39
平均は39です
20/3 of this average
この平均の 20/3
More than 100 students finally got this prize
最終的に100人以上の学生がこの賞を獲得しました
It's the classmate who wrote 26
26を書いたのは同級生です
I just talked about the economists at Caltech
先ほどカリフォルニア工科大学の経済学者について話しました。
his board of trustees at caltech
彼はカリフォルニア工科大学の理事です
do the same thing
同じことをする
His average is 9
彼の平均は9です
Game Theory at Yale University
イェール大学でのゲーム理論
The average in that class is 13
そのクラスの平均は13です
I'll start with the conclusion
結論から言います
If a person is really that rational
もし人間が本当にそこまで合理的なら
And he keeps on reasoning
そして彼は推理を続ける
Logically speaking, if everyone is so rational
論理的に言えば、誰もがとても合理的であれば、
That number should be 0
その数値は 0 である必要があります
should be 0
0である必要があります
then why let's see
それではなぜ見てみましょう
we have to have a hypothesis
仮説を立てる必要がある
Everyone wants to maximize their own interests
誰もが自分の利益を最大化したいと考えています
That is to say, you must get
つまり、取得する必要があります
hope you get this prize
あなたがこの賞を獲得できることを願っています
and you're assuming that other people are like you
そしてあなたは他の人も自分と同じだと思い込んでいる
also the same
また同じです
is perfectly rational
完全に合理的です
Then you have to do this kind of repetitive
次に、このような繰り返しを行う必要があります
this rational analysis
この合理的な分析
then you can take a look
それなら見てみてください
0 to 100
0～100
You can first think of
まず考えられるのは
if it is random for everyone
それが全員にとってランダムであれば
its average is 33
その平均は33です
So 2/3 is 22
つまり 2/3 は 22 です
right
右
this is an idea
これはアイデアです
That assumes everyone has learned
それは誰もが学んだことを前提としています
what is this random assignment
このランダムな割り当ては何ですか
Then you figure it out to be 33
そしたら、33歳だったことがわかりました
then you want
それならあなたは欲しいです
you know 33 you also assume each
33 あなたもそれぞれを想定しています
Others are as rational as you
他の人もあなたと同じくらい合理的です
right
右
So what is the value it calculates
それで計算される値は何ですか
also 33
33も
Well if everyone knows it's 33
まあ、みんなが知っていれば、それは33です
you write 22
あなたは22と書きます
Your chance to get this prize
この賞品を手に入れるチャンス
because everyone writes the same
みんな同じこと書いてるから
so you're pushing down
だからあなたは押し下げています
then you know what to say
それなら何を言えばいいかわかるでしょう
I'm thinking down
考え込んでいる
Everyone is equally rational
誰もが平等に合理的です
just write 22
22とだけ書いてください
right
右
2/3 of 22
22/3
you've been taking it off
あなたはそれを脱いでいます
Finally it becomes 0
最終的には0になります
right
右
but some people are smart
でも賢い人もいる
need to know say
言う必要がある
Everyone is willing to spend so much time thinking about this question
誰もがこの質問について考えることに非常に多くの時間を費やしたいと考えています
So why did Caltech's board become long?
では、なぜカリフォルニア工科大学の取締役会は長くなったのでしょうか?
He knows that some people don't think so much
あまり考えない人もいることを彼は知っている
So he guessed that we should adjust it up
それで彼はそれを調整すべきだと推測した
The one at Yanlu University is 13
燕鹿大学の人は13歳
Our Taiwan University students are more modest
台湾大学の学生はもっと謙虚です
Yes 39 20
はい 39 20
So his average is 26
つまり彼の平均は26です
in this game
このゲームでは
If you fill in more than 67, it is completely irrational
67以上記入すると完全に不合理になります
right?
右？
Because two-thirds of the average
平均の3分の2だから
Suppose everyone writes 100
全員が 100 と書いたとします。
That average is at least 67
その平均は少なくとも67です
Then you see if our classmates have written more than 67
次に、クラスメートが 67 を超える文章を書いたかどうかを見てみましょう。
Yes, there are still many
はい、まだたくさんあります
still twenty
まだ二十歳
so you can understand
だからあなたは理解できます
That is to say, you have to conduct a rational analysis
つまり、合理的な分析を行う必要があります
The first one is your ability
まずはあなたの能力です
second you have enough time
次に、十分な時間があります
The third one you may have some knowledge
3番目は、ある程度の知識があるかもしれません
Fourth, you may have to listen to the speech
第四に、スピーチを聞かなければならないかもしれません
The fourth is my own
4枚目は自分のものです
So this is the rational choice
したがって、これが合理的な選択です
Are we capable enough
私たちには十分な能力があるだろうか
This issue is not very new
この問題はそれほど新しいものではありません
not a new problem either
新しい問題でもない
Actually around the 1960s
実は1960年代頃
another nobel
別のノーベル
Economics or Psychology
経済学とか心理学とか
economics without psychology
心理学のない経済学
A professor of beauty in Karaji
カラジの美容教授
Called Herbert Simon mentioned that
ハーバート・サイモンと呼ばれる者はこう述べた
our bounded rationality
私たちの限界のある合理性
we are not so perfectly rational
私たちはそれほど完璧に合理的ではありません
This is what we can see
これが私たちが見ることができるものです
From this example it can be seen that
この例からわかるのは、
Human rationality is not as we imagined
人間の理性は想像通りではない
so perfect
その完璧な
Then we just mentioned
それから、先ほども言いましたが、
short term benefit
短期的な利益
with long-term benefits
長期的なメリットがある
What is the relationship between
間の関係は何ですか
is whether we will
するかどうかです
for the long-term benefit
長期的な利益のために
at the expense of this short-term benefit
この短期的な利益を犠牲にして
Then when Arie is what I just said
それから、アリーが今言ったことになると、
write predictable this irrational this academic
予測可能なことを書く これは非合理的 この学術的
He said most of us
彼は私たちのほとんどがこう言いました
see short-term benefits
短期的なメリットを見る
we usually enjoy it right away
私たちは通常すぐにそれを楽しみます
long time we will wait
長い間私たちは待ちます
This can't wait that long anyway
とにかくそんなに長く待つことはできません
then he made a
それから彼は作った
did a this this this research
これをこの調査で行いました
This research seems to be very simple
この研究はとても簡単そうに見えますが、
very simple
とてもシンプルな
Well, this is actually in the school
まあ、これは実際に学校にあります
We often encounter
私たちはよく遭遇します
Then he will be divided into three groups
それから彼は3つのグループに分けられます
ABC three groups
ABC三組
The first group is to submit three reports together at the end of the term
最初のグループは学期末に 3 つのレポートをまとめて提出します。
That's only twelve weeks
それはたったの12週間です
This is the word of the Quote
これは名言の言葉です
The second group is the teacher's rule
2番目のグループは先生のルールです
fourth week second week
第４週目 第２週目
In the eighth week and the twelfth week, you must teach the report you want to teach
8週目と12週目は教えたいレポートを教えなければなりません
The third group is set by the students themselves to teach the time of three feet
3 番目のグループは、生徒自身が 3 フィートの時間を教えるために設定します。
But as long as you teach, you will deduct 1% of the points for every day you teach
ただし、教えている限り、毎日教えるごとに 1% のポイントが差し引かれます。
So we now have three groups
これで 3 つのグループができました
This is the third group, and the students set the time for teaching three feet
これは 3 番目のグループで、生徒たちは 3 フィートを教える時間を設定しました。
Commitment to teach the first point and report the second point when
最初のポイントを教え、2 番目のポイントを報告するという約束
It can be from the first week to the tenth week
最初の週から10週目まで可能です
You have complete freedom to set the time you want to teach the presentation
プレゼンテーションを教える時間を完全に自由に設定できます
Then he took three classes, and the places where he did his research were all in these prestigious schools in the Ivy League
それから彼は 3 つの授業を受け、研究を行った場所はすべてアイビー リーグの名門校でした。
Harvard Yale places
ハーバード・エール大学の場所
The performance of the whole school, V is the best
全校のパフォーマンス、Vが最高
What is V?
Vとは何ですか？
prescribed by the teacher
先生に処方された
When was it handed in?
いつ渡されましたか?
And then? What comes next?
そして、次に何が起こるのでしょうか?
followed by C
続いてC
It is when the students themselves promise to hand in
それは生徒自身が提出することを約束したときです
What about the worst?
最悪の場合はどうでしょうか？
The worst is A
一番悪いのはAです
Submit a three-point report at the end of the term
期末に3点レポートを提出
So why is it such a bad idea to hand in three-point reports together at the end of the term?
では、なぜ期末に3点レポートをまとめて提出することがそれほど悪いのでしょうか?
because of the report
報告のせいで
Anyway, twelve weeks later.
とにかく、12週間後。
So there is a community in the middle
真ん中にコミュニティがあります
what are you going to do
何をする？
I want to help people run for election.
私は人々が選挙に立候補するのを手伝いたいと思っています。
Or go to work, wait
それとも仕事に行って待ってください
Anyway, let's play first.
とにかく、まずは遊んでみましょう。
he is dying
彼は死にかけている
Let's hold Buddha's feet together, this us
仏様の足を合わせましょう、この私たち
very simple
とてもシンプルな
all know
みんな知ってる
That
それか
it's interesting
それは面白い
looks like
のように見える
It seems that even in the US
アメリカでもあるらしい
even in the US
アメリカでも
Even though there may be teacher rules in the U.S.
アメリカには教師の規則があるかもしれませんが、
The situation he behaved
彼が行動した状況
will be the best
最高になります
But you have to pay attention to one thing
しかし、一つ注意しなければならないことがある
he carefully analyzed
彼は注意深く分析した
to analyze carefully
注意深く分析する
That is to say, there are students who promise to hand in
つまり、提出することを約束する学生がいるということです。
Although his achievement is in the middle
彼の成績は中程度だが
but a very interesting thing
しかし、非常に興味深いことです
If the promise he wrote himself is delivered to someone who can do it
自分で書いた約束ができる人に届けば
Actually he's doing very well
実際、彼はとてもうまくやっている
Why does C get worse?
なぜCは悪化するのでしょうか？
It's because these braggarts said when they would hand in
こいつらの強がりたちがいつ提出するって言ったからだよ
but not on time
でも間に合わない
As a result, the results of the C group are pulled down
その結果、Cグループの成績が引き下げられる
Otherwise he wouldn't have performed no worse than an A
そうでなければ彼はA以下の成績にはならなかったでしょう
No less than B No less than B No less than the teacher stipulated
B以上 B以上 教師の定める以上
I don't want to give you a false impression about this research.
この研究について誤った印象を与えたくないのです。
Because the teacher may represent the country or the government
教師は国や政府を代表する場合があるため
We just want an authoritarian dictatorship to set what time
私たちは権威主義的な独裁政権が時間を設定したいだけです
It tells you that you must complete the efficiency and the result will be the best.
効率よくやり遂げれば最高の結果が得られることを教えてくれます。
Academic performance will be the best
学業成績は最高になります
So one cylinder is the best
したがって、1気筒が最適です
right
右
that or
それか
stop here
ここで止​​まって
So this self-sufficiency
つまりこの自給自足は
if autonomy is possible
自主性が可能であれば
In fact, his results are not too bad.
実際、彼の成績はそれほど悪くない。
The point is that there will always be a minority
重要なのは、常に少数派が存在するということです
There are a few people he can't help
彼には助けられない人が何人かいる
For what's going to happen twelve weeks from now
今から12週間後に何が起こるかについて
His blood score is actually very important to him.
実際、彼の血液スコアは彼にとって非常に重要です。
But at the moment his interests
しかし現時点での彼の興味は
What are you doing playing?
何をして遊んでるの？
or just go and listen to a professor speak
あるいは教授の話を聞きに行ってください
If I tell you to go back and prepare for the midterm exam, you don't want it.
戻って中間試験の準備をしなさいと言っても、あなたはそれを望まないでしょう。
like help
助けてみたい
Then this will affect your preparation for this class
そうなると、このクラスの準備に影響が出ます
But once you are autonomous
しかし、一旦自立すると、
Although this C is between B and C
このCはBとCの間ですが
In fact, his effect is also good.
実際、彼の効果も優れています。
So if we want to be able to overcome this short-term benefit
したがって、この短期的な利点を克服したい場合は、
Then do some regulation on your own initiative
だったら自主的に規制しろよ
So if you release it, in fact it can still be solved
つまり、解放しても、実際にはまだ解決できるのです
can still solve the problem of delay
遅延の問題はまだ解決できる
for the long-term benefit
長期的な利益のために
It's this effect to complete
このエフェクトで完成です
So this is the second experiment
ということで2回目の実験です
The third experiment was
3つ目の実験は、
Let's go back to the fundamental question
根本的な質問に戻りましょう
Are people so rational?
人はそんなに合理的ですか？
This is the third experiment is will you cheat
これは 3 番目の実験です。不正行為をしますか?
Anyway, he thinks about these things every day
とにかく彼は毎日こんなことを考えている
these studies
これらの研究
I just told you where he did the research
彼がどこで調査を行ったかを話したばかりです
At Harvard, MIT, Yale, Britston, UZL
ハーバード大学、MIT、エール大学、ブリットストン、UZL
these schools
これらの学校
he has 50 questions
彼には50の質問がある
10 cents for each correct answer
正解ごとに 10 セント
10 cents per catty
1斤あたり10セント
he has four groups
彼には4つのグループがある
He is the first to issue an answer ticket
彼は最初に回答チケットを発行した人です
Send out the topic, the booklet first, and send out a copy of this booklet first
トピック、小冊子を最初に送信し、この小冊子のコピーを最初に送信します
You write the answer on the question book
問題集に答えを書きます
About 40 minutes after writing the answer
回答を書いてから約40分が経過しました
40 minutes until you finish writing
書き終わるまであと40分
He is sending you an answer card to fill in with 2B pliers
彼はあなたに 2B ペンチで記入するための回答カードを送っています
I want you to lift it up
持ち上げてほしい
This control group is after you fill out the answer card
このコントロール グループは、回答カードに記入した後のものです。
by the teacher
先生によって
in this case
この場合
52 questions total average
合計平均52問
Average 32.6 correct answers
平均正解数 32.6
32.6
３２。６
So it means that he can get more than 3 dollars
つまり、彼は3ドル以上を得ることができるということです
There are not many reporters
記者が少ない
not many
あまり多くない
What about the second group?
2番目のグループはどうでしょうか？
What about the second group and the first group?
2番目のグループと最初のグループはどうでしょうか？
After he handed out the answer card himself
彼が自ら解答カードを配った後、
After sending out the answer card for you to fill out
回答カードを送信した後、記入してください
give you the correct answer
正しい答えを教えてください
you go right
あなたは右に行きます
How many questions did you get right?
あなたは何問正解できましたか？
36.2
３６。２
Of course he's sure
もちろん彼は確信している
Group 1234 basically has the same knowledge and abilities
グループ1234は基本的に同じ知識と能力を持っています
And he did look at this answer card of his
そして彼は自分の解答カードを見た
Does his answer card have the trace of the picture modification?
彼の解答用紙には写真修正の痕跡はあるのか？
He can know with certainty that
彼はそれを確実に知ることができる
This 4.2 is cheating
この 4.2 は不正行為です
The result after changing the graph
グラフを変更した結果
the third one
3番目の
The third one is also the answer
3つ目も答えです
And what makes it even harder for you to track is
そして、追跡をさらに困難にしているのは、
He took the topic paper
彼は話題の論文を取り上げた
you can put it in a sleeping paper machine
スリーピング抄紙機に入れてもいいよ
you destroy it
あなたがそれを破壊します
But your answer card is still reserved for this host of that study.
ただし、あなたの回答カードは、その研究のこのホストのためにまだ予約されています。
The fourth group is
4番目のグループは、
How much does it cost? Anyway, you take it yourself, it doesn't matter
いくらかかりますか? とにかく自分で受け取ってください、問題ありません
This is completely unrestricted, then you have to find out
これは完全に制限されていないため、確認する必要があります
From the second group, the third group, and the fourth group, in fact, it correctly answers the difference in this question
2番目のグループ、3番目のグループ、4番目のグループから、この質問の違いを実際に答えました
There is not much difference in this
これに関してはあまり違いはありません
So this is very surprising, why?
これは非常に驚くべきことですが、なぜでしょうか?
Very surprised, that is to say, when we are speculating, when we are cheating
非常に驚いたとき、つまり、推測しているとき、不正行為をしているとき
We're not going to calculate the cost of getting caught
捕まった場合のコストを計算するつもりはありません
Why do you say that about the relationship with the benefits you get?
給付金との関係でなぜそんなことを言うのですか。
Like this you answer the answer yourself, but the one written above your title
このようにあなたは自分で答えますが、タイトルの上に書かれたものは
The answers written on the question paper are the same as those on the answer coupon.
問題用紙に記載されている答えは、解答用紙に記載されているものと同じです。
Our researchers are right about this, then this
私たちの研究者はこれについては正しい、そしてこれは
By the time of the fourth group, there is almost no evidence
4番目のグループの時点では、証拠はほとんどありません
No one knows you, it's not that no one knows
誰もあなたのことを知らない、誰も知らないわけではない
Can't find it out, there's nothing in the whole
見つからない、全体的に何もない
How is the whole class?
クラス全体の様子はどうですか？
But there is no way to identify individuals
ただし個人を特定する方法はありません
Logically speaking, it's impossible to get caught like this.
論理的に言えば、このように捕まることは不可能です。
you can brag
自慢できます
You just straight out of this jar
あなたはこの瓶から出てきたばかりです
take four or five bucks
4ドルか5ドルを取る
means you got it right
あなたは正しく理解したという意味です
This kind of reward to you later
このようなご褒美は後であなたに
we will not calculate
私たちは計算しません
look
見て
This one has the highest risk of getting caught
こいつが捕まるリスクが一番高い
this minimum
この最低限の
But the way we behave
しかし、私たちの振る舞い方は、
one time
一度
have you been caught
捕まったの？
when you want to cheat
騙したいとき
when there is an opportunity to cheat
不正行為をする機会があるとき
risk of getting caught
捕まる危険性
you're not thinking
あなたは考えていません
not
いいえ
than the cost-benefit relationship between the
の費用対効果の関係よりも、
you don't think so much
あなたはあまり考えていません
in this experiment
この実験では
We can see that
それがわかります
That is to say, if ethics and norms
つまり、倫理や規範があれば、
when not so mandatory
それほど義務ではない場合
That man has this head muscle
あの人はこの頭の筋肉を持っています
There is a tendency to speculate
憶測する傾向がある
so we say dishonest
だから私たちは不誠実だと言うのです
Of course he destroys
もちろん彼は破壊します
This transaction in the entire market
市場全体におけるこの取引
Same time as Osha
オシャと同じ時期
williamson won the nobel prize in economics
ウィリアムソンはノーベル経済学賞を受賞した
He mentioned that this opportunism
彼はこの日和見主義について述べた
is to invalidate the market
市場を無効にすることです
quite an important factor
かなり重要な要素
market failure
市場の失敗
At the level of the human actor there are two
人間の俳優のレベルでは 2 つあります。
bounded rationality
限定合理性
one is opportunism
一つはご都合主義です
will make this market impossible to operate
この市場は運営できなくなるだろう
that's dishonest
それは不誠実です
he can also destroy
彼は破壊することもできる
The sense of trust in the entire community members
コミュニティメンバー全体への信頼感
No one wants to follow this norm
誰もこの規範に従いたくありません
what i mean is
私が言いたいのは
actually dishonest
実は不誠実
lack of trust
信頼の欠如
Not only the operation of the market is no way
市場の運営だけではだめだ
what i mentioned
私が言及したこと
That is to say, it is developed spontaneously by actors
つまり、俳優によって自発的に開発される
the system that governs that public good
その公益を管理するシステム
he can't help
彼は助けることができない
also does not work
も機能しません
In this example inside
この例では内部
all i want to say is to say
私が言いたいのは言いたいことだけです
In fact, people are not so
実際のところ、人間はそうではありません
as rational as we imagined
私たちが想像していた通り合理的
So if we're not that rational
だから、もし私たちがそこまで合理的でないとしたら、
In this uncertain environment
この不確かな環境の中で
We just saw that we have no way to calculate
計算する方法がないことがわかりました
when
いつ
how to when
いつどうやって
can maximize their own interests
自分の利益を最大化できる
The second experiment is to say
2番目の実験は、次のことを言います。
We'll see short-term benefits of this
これによる短期的なメリットが分かるだろう
we are priority
私たちが優先です
but we often forget
しかし私たちはしばしば忘れてしまいます
There are long-term benefits of this
これには長期的なメリットがあります
The third is this rational ability
3つ目はこの合理的能力です
if not so full
それほどいっぱいではない場合
then he might be involved in this
そうすれば彼はこれに関わっているかもしれない
this stage of this development of morality
道徳の発達のこの段階
no way to go any further
これ以上進む方法はありません
that is
あれは
your code of ethics
あなたの倫理規定
the ability to abide by the code of ethics
倫理規定を遵守する能力
not so solid
それほどしっかりしていない
not so stable
あまり安定していない
That
それか
he has the potential to cause opportunism
彼はご都合主義を引き起こす可能性がある
So what I'm actually trying to say here is to say
ここで私が実際に言いたいのは、
Reason of course it is for intelligence
理由はもちろん知性のためです
is a very important element
非常に重要な要素です
but I think it's necessary
でもそれは必要だと思う
it is not a sufficient condition
それは十分条件ではありません
That reason it is for this morality this development
だからこそこの道徳のためにこの開発はある
In fact it is very important
実はそれはとても重要なことなのです
And this psychologist in Switzerland
そしてこのスイスの心理学者は
Peter J.
ピーター J.
And then this one from Harvard University
そして、これはハーバード大学からのものです
The professor of psychology
心理学の教授
Kopach he referred to this moral development
コパッチはこの道徳的発展について言及した
different stage
違うステージ
In fact, based on the development of morality
実際、道徳の発達に基づいて、
must also be built on
も構築する必要があります
this rational faculty
この合理的な能力
Then this ability is insufficient
それではこの能力では不十分です
How to do it
どうやってするの
What to do if the ability is insufficient
能力が足りない場合はどうするか
What about lack of rational ability?
合理的能力の欠如についてはどうですか？
Then we can only see if there is a more rational
そうすれば、より合理的な方法があるかどうかを確認することしかできません。
this way
こちらです
then we just mentioned
それから、先ほども言いましたが
That is to say, a public discussion in a community
つまり、コミュニティでの公開討論です。
things i know
私が知っていること
i may have some limitations
いくつか制限があるかもしれない
Then I can discuss with other people
そうすれば他の人と話し合えるよ
It might be possible to develop a more rational
もっと合理的な方法を開発できるかもしれない
This mechanism of supervision and punishment
この監視と懲罰の仕組み
like this fishing village in this alenya in Türkiye
トゥルキエのこのアレニャの漁村のように
Or that we develop a more pronounced morality
あるいは、私たちがより顕著な道徳性を身につけること
Or this kind of constraint of the specification
あるいはこのような仕様の制約
that would make our kind of bounded rationality
それは私たちのような限界のある合理性を作るでしょう
The problem with opportunism
ご都合主義の問題
can get some restrictions
いくつかの制限を受ける可能性があります
As for this change in behavioral theory
この行動理論の変化については
I will not talk for now
今のところ話さないよ
skip it first
最初にスキップしてください
This is because there is not enough time
時間が足りないからだ
I just mentioned that
先ほども言いましたが、
This study from Ostron
オストロンによるこの研究
Whether people are so rational is a question
人間がそこまで合理的かどうかは疑問だ
The second question is
2番目の質問は、
Is that man like we said
あの男は私たちが言った通りですか
so selfish
とても利己的です
So I'm giving two different messages here
そこで私はここで 2 つの異なるメッセージを伝えます
One is an anthropologist and this economist
一人は人類学者で、この人は経済学者です
This study in the Garden Out Society
Garden Out Society でのこの研究
The other one is social members of different age groups
もう1つは、さまざまな年齢層の社会人です
Comparison among different indigenous societies
さまざまな先住民社会間の比較
I mostly based it on the book
ほとんど本を参考にしました
It was published by Oxford University in 2003
2003年にオックスフォード大学から出版されました
It is the study of the social basis of human beings
人間の社会的基盤を研究する学問です
What about his research?
彼の研究についてはどうですか？
you can see this cover
この表紙を見るとわかります
He is in 15 indigenous communities
彼は 15 の先住民コミュニティに住んでいます
probably in the past ten years
おそらく過去10年間で
where are they
彼らはどこにいる
they are at this age
彼らはこの年齢です
over the past ten years they
過去10年間、彼らは
where are they
彼らはどこにいる
economist psychologist
経済学者心理学者
combined with anthropologists
人類学者と協力して
to do this research
この研究をするために
The location of this study
この研究の場所
What about the research site?
研究現場はどうでしょうか？
from africa
アフリカから
Then to this Indonesia
そしてこのインドネシアへ
Then
それから
New Guinea
ニューギニア
then to this
それからこれに
latin america
ラテンアメリカ
latin america is in bolivia
ラテンアメリカはボリビアにある
then bolivia
それからボリビア
Peru and Ecuador
ペルーとエクアドル
these places
これらの場所
I think this book is quite interesting
この本はかなり面白いと思います
because we can see the differences between different societies
異なる社会の違いが分かるからです
In fact, they want to do this kind of research in this kind of primitive tribe
実際、彼らはこの種の原始部族でこの種の研究をしたいと考えています
It will probably take two or three years
たぶん2、3年はかかるだろう
But they are taking the same data collection method
しかし、彼らは同じデータ収集アプローチを採用しています
Why do they cooperate with economists in the collection of data
なぜ彼らはデータ収集において経済学者と協力するのか
Because they mainly use this game
彼らは主にこのゲームを使用しているため、
game of economic resource allocation
経済資源配分のゲーム
This is of course more difficult
もちろんこれはもっと難しいです
They mainly have three different ways of playing
主に3つの異なる遊び方があります
This relates to what I'm going to talk about later.
これは、後で説明することに関係します。
The first game called Dictator
最初のゲーム「ディクテーター」
The dictator's game is me as the allocator of resources
独裁者のゲームは資源の割り当て者としての私だ
If I have a hundred dollars in my hand
もし私が手に100ドルを持っていたら
I can assign to this gentleman
この紳士に任せることができます
I can totally decide how much money I want to allocate to him
私は彼にどれだけのお金を割り当てたいかを完全に決めることができます
i am a dictator
私は独裁者です
I have a hundred yuan, and I can allocate as much as you want
私は百元持っています、あなたが望むだけ割り当ててもいいです
if i was completely self-reliant
もし私が完全に自立していたら
i'm a dictator now i have a hundred dollars
私は今独裁者です、私は100ドルを持っています
how much do you think i will give him
私は彼にいくらあげると思いますか
How much? Not even a dime
いくら? 一銭にも満たない
so i can stand on my own
だから私は自分で立つことができます
Otherwise, it would be wrong for me to give him a dollar.
そうでなければ、私が彼に1ドルも渡すのは間違っているでしょう。
I'm a dictator, he can't do anything to me
私は独裁者、彼は私に何もできない
Right? What missiles do I have? What planes do I have?
そうですか? 私はどんなミサイルを持っていますか? 私はどんな飛行機を持っていますか?
that can't do anything to me ? he has nothing
それは私には何もできないのですか？彼は何も持っていません
This is the first dictator of this game
これがこのゲームの最初の独裁者です
What about the second one?
2番目のものはどうですか？
The second game of his is the game of ultimatum
彼の第二試合は最後通牒のゲームだ
the game is the same
ゲームは同じです
i have a hundred dollars
私は100ドルを持っています
Then I decide how much to allocate to him
それから私は彼にどれだけ割り当てるかを決めます
but he has a
しかし彼は
Unlike the dictator just now
さっきの独裁者と違って
So decide to accept or not
それで受け入れるか受け入れないかを決める
Suppose I have one hundred yuan, I give him twenty, and I keep eighty for myself
私が100元を持っていて、20元を彼に渡し、80元を自分用に取っておくとします。
if he decides not to accept
彼が受け入れないと決めた場合
Please be aware of this
ご了承ください。
we two have nothing
私たち二人には何もありません
Do you understand?
わかりますか？
That is, I have a hundred dollars and give him twenty dollars
つまり、私は 100 ドルを持っているので、彼に 20 ドルをあげます
The ultimatum is here
最後通牒がここにある
That's how I divide resources now
それが今私がリソースを分割する方法です
Then you have to decide whether you accept it or not
その後、それを受け入れるかどうかを決定する必要があります
The condition I put forward
私が出した条件
I keep eighty, you take twenty
私は80個を維持しますが、あなたは20個かかります
if you don't agree
同意しない場合
you won't get a dime
一銭も得られないでしょう
I can't get a dime
一銭ももらえない
So this is the game of ultimatum
つまりこれは最後通牒のゲームだ
let's see
どれどれ
They are in these fifteen different circles out of society
彼らは社会の外の15の異なるサークルに属しています
They all used something like this
みんなこんな感じのものを使っていました
This is the game of ultimatum
これは最後通牒のゲームだ
The game of ultimatum
最後通牒のゲーム
Then you can see in these sixteen
そうすると、この 16 個を見ればわかります。
fifteen different places
15の異なる場所
There is a P word treasure interspersed in the middle
真ん中にPワードの宝物がちりばめられています
This is America's P
これがアメリカのPです
0.5 means you spend the money you have
0.5は、持っているお金をすべて使うことを意味します
researchers give you money
研究者はお金をくれる
You give half to each other
半分ずつお互いにあげ合うんだよ
divide the circle
円を分割する
The size of the circle in the middle represents
真ん中の円の大きさは
The members of the study who participated in the test
テストに参加した研究メンバー
He gives half to the other party
彼は半分を相手に渡す
The size of the ratio that allocates half to the other party
半分を相手に割り当てる割合の大きさ
So guys in this chart you can see
このグラフを見ればわかるように、
you can see
見ることができます
This P word treasure in the United States
アメリカのこのPワードの宝物
About half of the study participants
研究参加者の約半数が
if he gets 100
彼が100点を取ったら
in the ultimatum game
最後通告ゲームで
he will assign to each other
彼はお互いに割り当てます
about 50 yuan
約50元
Usually the chances of being rejected in this case are not high
通常、この場合に拒否される可能性は高くありません
look at the bottom
一番下を見てください
These two places are in Miru
Miru にはこの 2 つの場所があります
This one is in Milu, and this one is in Erhuadu
これはミルにあり、これは二花都にあります
You can take a look at this in Miru
Miruでご覧いただけます
What is the most people give it?
一番多くの人があげているものは何でしょうか？
15%
１５％
That is 100 yuan, it gives 15 yuan to the other party
それは100元です、相手に与えるのは15元です
And surprisingly, 85 yuan
そして驚くことに85元
That is 100 yuan, you give the other party 15 yuan and you keep 85 yuan
つまり100元、あなたは相手に15元渡し、あなたは85元を手元に残します
Here its rejection is very very low
ここでの拒否率は非常に低いです
very very low
とてもとても低い
Then this is somewhat different from our general understanding.
それでは、これは私たちの一般的な理解とは多少異なります。
Basically speaking, the original society
基本的に本来の社会は、
They can be said to be a cooperative economy
協同組合経済とも言える
Like P word treasure, of course it is a kind of capitalism
Pワードの宝物のように、もちろんそれは一種の資本主義です
the shape of the economy
経済の形
a lot of competition
たくさんの競争
then emphasize personal interests
それから個人的な利益を強調する
right
右
then in this case
それはこの場合
why would he
なぜ彼は
Everyone give 50
みんな50あげて
Give the other party 50 out of 100 yuan
100元のうち50元を相手に渡す
Instead, what we see
代わりに、私たちが見ているものは、
the following
以下
The entire 15 tribes
15部族全体
Distinguished in various parts of the world
世界各地で名声を博している
he is a food
彼は食べ物です
hit this hand cracked thing
この手をひび割れたものにぶつけてください
must be shared
共有しなければならない
This original society
この本来の社会
Relatively speaking
相対的に言えば
them
彼ら
provide to
提供する
Others
その他
or this member of his tribe
または彼の部族のこのメンバー
What about the resources given to him?
彼に与えられた資源はどうなるのでしょうか？
Relatively speaking
相対的に言えば
not what we imagined
私たちが想像していたものではありません
so many
とてもたくさんの
not as much as we thought
私たちが思っていたほどではない
then we are here
それなら私たちはここにいます
I'm here
私はここにいます
he
他
don't explain too much about this
これについてはあまり説明しないでください
because this
なぜならこれは
is quite complicated
かなり複雑です
quite complicated
かなり複雑な
I just talk
ただ話すだけです
50% on this P-SYB
この P-SYB の 50%
This involves the receiver
これには受信機が関係します
one of his thoughts on fairness
公平性についての彼の考えの一つ
That is to say
つまり
In a society like America
アメリカのような社会では
most people would think
ほとんどの人はこう思うだろう
what is a fair
フェアとは何ですか
This way of resource allocation
このようなリソースの割り当て方法
It's everyone's half and half
みんな半々だよ
that in this ultimatum game
それがこの最後通牒ゲームで
who you want to allocate resources to
リソースを誰に割り当てたいか
you must think of one thing
あなたは一つのことを考えなければなりません
If I allocate this resource
このリソースを割り当てると
I don't take into account the other person's feelings and thoughts
相手の気持ちや考えを考慮しない
we may not get both
両方手に入らないかもしれない
so what
だから何
Your best bet is you don't get rejected
最善の策は拒否されないことです
if you understand each other
お互いを理解できれば
acceptable
許容できる
think this is a fair distribution
これが公平な分配だと思う
If this ratio is 50%
この比率が50%だとすると
your best way
あなたの最善の方法
You are 50%
あなたは50%です
to each other
お互いに
Only in this way can you get this resource
この方法でのみこのリソースを入手できます
in other societies
他の社会では
like this one in indonesia
インドネシアのこれのように
Then this is more than what Pizibao offers
これは Pizibao が提供するもの以上のものです
that's it you can see
それがわかります
It's up to 50%
最大50%です
But most of them are more than 50%
しかし、そのほとんどが50％を超えています。
most are over 50%
ほとんどが50%を超えています
What kind of society is this?
これはどのような社会ですか？
It is the first goldfish specifically listed in the Indonesian sea
インドネシア海で特別に指定された初めての金魚です。
Dedicated to the first goldfish
最初の金魚に捧げます
Then you know how to shoot a big goldfish
そうすれば、大きな金魚を撃つ方法がわかります
It may have to be forty or fifty people together
40人か50人が集まる必要があるかもしれない
Together
一緒
Very detailed and precise division of labor
非常に詳細かつ正確な分業
so in this place
だからこの場所で
What kind of communication among group members do they
グループメンバー間でどのようなコミュニケーションをとっているのか
this social bond
この社会的な絆
and the one who shared
そしてシェアしてくれた人
specification can say
仕様は言える
is the ultimate state
究極の状態です
So he would rather give the other party a little more
だから彼はむしろ相手にもう少し多くを与えたいと思う
I would rather give each other more
むしろお互いにもっと与え合いたい
so this is very special
だからこれはとても特別なことだよ
the other i'm here
もう一人は私はここにいます
I won't explain too much
あまり説明しません
But the point here is to say
しかし、ここで重要なのは、
inside a community
コミュニティの中で
within a community
コミュニティで
He developed it because of his lifestyle
彼は自分のライフスタイルのためにそれを開発しました
that norm and value
その規範と価値観
in fact affects
実際に影響を与える
He is in this game of economic resource allocation
彼は経済資源の配分というゲームに参加している
how does he do the distribution
彼はどのように配布を行っていますか
You can see this chart more clearly
このグラフをより明確に見ることができます
It can be seen more clearly that
さらにはっきりとわかるのは、
We just talked about this in Indonesia
ちょうどインドネシアでこのことについて話し合ったところです
He's in this game of ultimatum
彼は最後通牒のゲームに参加している
he gave the most
彼は一番多くを与えてくれた
What about this one?
これはどうですか？
this one
これです
This one is the game of the dictator
これは独裁者のゲームだ
That is to say
つまり
i have a hundred dollars
私は100ドルを持っています
how much for you
あなたにいくらですか
There is no way for the other party to refuse
相手には拒否の余地がない
So in this dictator's game
つまり、この独裁者のゲームでは
He will clearly show up saying
彼は明らかにこう言って現れるだろう
Are we so Chilean
私たちはとてもチリ人ですか？
You can take a look
見てみることができます
This is an American worker
こちらはアメリカ人労働者です
Then this black one is
じゃあ、この黒いのは、
Is the Iraqi immigrants to the United States
米国へのイラク移民ですか
And then they have a small community of this
そして、彼らはこの小さなコミュニティを持っています
that in this gray
それはこの灰色の中で
The gray one is a college student
灰色の人は大学生です
this is a college student
これは大学生です
Then you can see that
そうすればわかります
in the middle
途中で
this is you have 100
これは100個持っています
You give the other party 50 yuan
相手に50元渡す
That's what we just talked about in the Dictator game
それはディクテーター ゲームで我々が言ったことです
you have 100 yuan
あなたは100元を持っています
You shouldn't give each other a dime
お互いに一銭も与えてはいけない
you are chile
あなたはチリです
right
右
So you see this worker in America
アメリカでこの労働者を見かけますね
This worker in the United States does not have nearly a million
米国のこの労働者は100万人近くも持っていない
70% when he has 100
彼が 100 を持っている場合は 70%
He will give the other party 50 yuan
彼は相手に50元を渡します
His percentage is higher in minority communities
彼の割合は少数派コミュニティでより高い
Nearly 80
80近く
Transnational Studies in Dictator's Game
独裁者のゲームにおける国境を越えた研究
usually no one
通常は誰もいない
Few studies were seen across different countries
さまざまな国で確認された研究はほとんどありません
I didn't see that someone said that they didn't share with each other at all.
誰かがお互いにまったく共有していないと言っているのを見ませんでした。
At least 20% more to 40%
少なくとも 20% 以上 40%
20% to 40% in the middle
真ん中の20%から40%
So we can compare from different groups
したがって、さまざまなグループから比較できます
We can see that
それがわかります
In fact, people are not as selfish as we think
実際、人は私たちが思っているほど利己的ではありません
But of course some people are very selfish
しかし、もちろん非常に利己的な人もいます
not a dime
一銭もありません
wait a minute we'll talk about a question
ちょっと待ってください、質問について話します
Of course some people are altruistic if they are not selfish
もちろん利己的ではなくても利他的な人もいます
some people are selfish
利己的な人もいます
what happens when they are together
彼らが一緒にいると何が起こるか
we'll see later
後で見てみましょう
Let's look at the different age groups
さまざまな年齢層を見てみましょう
I just talked about different societies
私はちょうどさまざまな社会について話しました
This comparison of members of different age groups
さまざまな年齢層のメンバーの比較
This is 7 years old and 10 years old
こちらは7歳と10歳です
11 years old 13 years old 17 years old
11歳 13歳 17歳
This one is female
こちらはメスです
this is male
これは男性です
you can see
見ることができます
This is from 20 coins you have
手持ちのコイン20枚からです
this is hero
これは英雄です
that's 20 coins
それは20コインです
How much do you give each other
お互いにいくらあげますか
that's a dictator
それは独裁者です
You can see this 7-year-old kid
この7歳の子供が見えます
he has 20 coins
彼はコインを20枚持っています
He will probably give the opponent an average
彼はおそらく相手に平均的な評価を与えるだろう
then the trend
それからトレンド
this girl
この少女
to 17 years old
17歳まで
Nothing much has changed with this
これに関しては特に何も変わっていない
good
良い
if you look at boys
男の子たちを見たら
Compare
比較
Probably in all studies probably have this
おそらくすべての研究にこれがあるでしょう
relatively consistent conclusion
比較的一貫した結論
Boys usually give less to each other
男の子は通常、お互いにあまり与えません
will be less
少なくなります
This is on research
これは研究中です
probably very clear
おそらく非常に明確です
a phenomenon
現象
so you can watch
だからあなたは見ることができます
Our little friend who was about seven years old
7歳くらいの私たちの小さな友達
He won't be what we imagined
彼は我々が想像していたものとは違うだろう
then this intelligence
それからこの知性
not so intelligent
それほど賢くない
Okay, let's see this in Taiwan
よし、台湾で見てみよう
This is our latest
これは私たちの最新のものです
In Penghu and in New Taipei City
澎湖県と新北市
the research done
行われた研究
i should be faster
私はもっ​​と速いはずです
so what
だから何
I give everyone
みんなにあげます
I'll just talk about this
これについてだけ話します
This is fifth grade
これは5年生です
this is seventh grade
これは7年生です
This is the eleventh grade
これは11年生です
Then let me tell you, please pay attention
それから、言っておきますが、注意してください
I'll talk about this row first
まずこの行について話します
it's a dictator's game
それは独裁者のゲームだ
That is to say, this kid has 30 yuan in his hand
つまり、この子の手には30元があるということです。
This is five years old, seven years old, eleven years old
これは5歳、7歳、11歳です
No, fifth grade, seventh grade, eleventh grade
いいえ、5 年生、7 年生、11 年生
It distributes the 30 yuan to the other party
30元を相手に分配する
Our sample adds up to
私たちのサンプルを合計すると、
There are about 400 students
生徒数は約400名
Each grade has about 100
各学年約100名
More than 100 or so
100多個左右
You can take a look
見てみることができます
Our kid in fifth grade
うちの子は5年生
It is assigned to each other with an average of 18.6
平均 18.6 で互いに割り当てられます。
That is to say it will be nearly more than half
つまり半分以上になるということです
Then the seventh grade is about 17.0
それから7年生は約17.0です
Then the eleventh grade
それから11年生
The student in the second year of high school is about 16.3
高校2年生の生徒は約16.3歳です。
So that compared to
つまり、比較すると
This student of ours is assigning this resource
私たちの生徒がこのリソースを配布しています
when giving to each other
お互いに与え合うとき
this time for the other party
今度は相手のために
He is quite generous
彼はとても寛大です
Not as Chilean as we thought
思ったほどチリっぽくない
Then we just mentioned that
それから、先ほども言いましたが、
from different tribes
さまざまな部族から
A Comparison of Different Original Owner Societies
さまざまな元の所有者団体の比較
Then to this kid of different ages
それから、このさまざまな年齢の子供に
We can see that any one
誰でもそれがわかります
we will see something like
次のようなものが表示されます
Even with this college student in the United States
アメリカのこの大学生でも
Some people are more Chilean
もっとチリっぽい人もいる
what about some people
一部の人はどうですか
he is generous or fair
彼は寛大または公正です
treat others
他人を扱う
So we are in a society
だから私たちは社会の中にいます
we are in a society
私たちは社会の中にいます
We are actually Chilean individuals
私たちは実はチリ人です
the altruistic other
利他的な他者
he is in a community
彼はコミュニティにいます
he will have some interaction
彼は何らかの交流を持つだろう
have some contacts
いくつかの連絡先を持っています
that was in 2003
それは2003年のことでした
Some scholars in this Switzerland
このスイスの学者の中には
the research they did
彼らが行った研究
What is their research doing
彼らの研究は何をしているのか
What you do is to say that in a game of public wealth
あなたがやっていることは、公共の富を賭けたゲームでそう言うことです
Let's see how everyone paid at the beginning
最初にみんながどのように支払ったかを見てみましょう
Then let this game of public wealth
それならこの公共の富のゲームをやろう
Continue to operate ten times, twenty times
10回、20回と稼働し続ける
The game of public goods is
公共財のゲームは、
Each of us has hands on hands Let's say we now have five people
私たちはそれぞれ手を携えています今、5人いるとしましょう
Each of us has 100 yuan
私たちはそれぞれ100元を持っています
Then our 100 yuan
それから私たちの100元
If I take out this 100 yuan
この100元を出したら
It's up to you to decide how much you want to spend out of 100 yuan
100元のうちいくら使うかはあなた次第です
5 or 10
5 または 10
after taking it out
取り出した後
It becomes this resource in a public
公開中のこのリソースになります
Then this researcher will multiply by three times
次に、この研究者は 3 倍を掛けます
if i take 5 dollars out
5ドル出したら
triple
トリプル
The three lists are 15
3 つのリストは 15
Multiplied by 15 and then scored for the five people participating in the public money game
15 を掛けて、公的マネー ゲームに参加している 5 人のスコアを計算します。
So a person can get three dollars
つまり、一人は 3 ドルを得ることができます
Fully self-reliant people in this public money game
この公的資金ゲームで完全に自立した人々
He doesn't have to take out a dime
彼は一銭も引き出す​​必要はない
but he just has to wait
でも彼はただ待つしかない
After someone else took out the money and tripled it
誰かがお金を引き出して3倍にした後
Naturally he can distribute the benefits
当然利益を分配できる
Get benefits
メリットを得る
In this public money game
この公的資金ゲームでは
You can see that at the beginning
それは冒頭でわかります
what everyone is willing to pay
誰もが喜んで支払うもの
there are many people willing to give
喜んで与えてくれる人がたくさんいる
But in this person who is willing to give
しかし、喜んで与えるこの人の中で
as he plays more public money games
彼がより多くの公的資金ゲームに参加するにつれて
Because everyone knows I don't have to pay
お金を払う必要がないことはみんな知っているから
I can also benefit
私も恩恵を受けることができます
So fewer and fewer people are willing to give
寄付する意欲のある人はますます少なくなっています
As a result those who think altruistically
その結果、利他的に考える人は、
He also refused to take out the money
彼はお金を引き出すことも拒否した
what did it become in the end
結局どうなったの
In the end it becomes in this game of public wealth
結局のところ、それはこの公共の富のゲームになる
After he ran 10 times 24
彼が 10 回走った後 24
no one wants to pay more
誰もそれ以上払いたくない
take a look at this chart
このチャートを見てください
This chart is actually very close to the one just now.
このチャートは実際には今のチャートに非常に近いものです。
is if we don't have participants
参加者がいない場合です
This possibility without any penalty
ペナルティなしでこの可能性
this game of public wealth
この公共の富を賭けたゲーム
when he got to the 10th time
10回目に到達したとき
willing to give
喜んで与える
This ratio has been decreasing
この割合は減少傾向にあります
keeps falling
落ち続ける
If you keep making him play 20 times
20回遊ばせ続けたら
Hardly anyone wants to throw money away anymore
もうお金をドブに捨てたい人はほとんどいないでしょう
Then if you have this mechanism of punishment
この罰のメカニズムがあるなら
That means we are now for the first time
つまり、私たちは今初めて
first game
最初のゲーム
Then I lose 3 yuan
そしたら3元損するよ
No one lost a dime
誰も一銭も損しなかった
what about me
私はどうなの
i can punish him
私は彼を罰することができます
i can deduct his money
彼のお金を差し引くことができます
what about this time
今回はどうですか
this time you can watch
今度は見ることができます
at the eleventh time
11回目で
When you add this penalty mechanism into
このペナルティメカニズムを追加すると、
The resources that everyone invests in this public good
誰もがこの公益のために投資するリソース
In the game of public goods
公共財のゲームにおいて
The possibility that you are willing to take your money out
お金を引き出すつもりがある可能性
The probability is significantly increased by this ratio
この比率により確率は大幅に増加します
Then let me talk about the first
それでは、最初のことについて話しましょう
when chileans hang out with altruistic people
チリ人が利他的な人々とつるむとき
Altruistic people are willing to give
利他的な人は喜んで与える
But altruistic people may be 30% 40%
でも利他的な人は30%か40%かもしれない
But 60% of them are from Chile
しかし、そのうちの60％はチリ出身です
totally unwilling to give
全く与える気がない
Altruistic people at this time
この時代の利他的な人々
he doesn't want to be a fool
彼は愚か者になりたくない
don't want to be a fool
バカになりたくない
So he won't pay anymore
だから彼はもう払いません
so you see here
それでここを見ます
Some people are willing to invest a lot of money
大金を投資したい人もいる
This proportion of increasing investment
増加する投資のこの割合
The proportion is getting lower and lower
割合はどんどん低くなっていきます
It would have been nearly 45%
45%近くあっただろう
tenth time here
ここで10回目
about twenty left
残り約20
It turns out that those who are willing to give selflessly
無私無欲に与えようとする人々は、
altruistic person
利他的な人
He doesn't want to pay anymore
彼はもう払いたくない
Then this research has a very important significance
そうなると、この研究は非常に重要な意味を持ちます
what does this mean
これは何を意味するのでしょうか
When we see this tragedy of so-called public goods
いわゆる公共財のこの悲劇を見るとき
When we see that people are very indifferent to public affairs
人々が公務に非常に無関心であるのを見ると、
Our first assumption shouldn't be that everyone is selfish
私たちの最初の前提は、誰もが利己的であるということではありません
our first
私たちの最初の
we might think about it
私たちはそれについて考えるかもしれません
At the last moment, everyone is unwilling to pay
最後の瞬間には誰もが支払いたくなくなります
some may be those who are highly altruistic
非常に利他的な人もいるかもしれない
He's been a fool for too long
彼はあまりにも長い間愚か者だった
been taken advantage of
利用された
So he was unwilling to continue to do such a thing in the end.
したがって、彼は結局そのようなことを続ける気はありませんでした。
Then this is the research team in Switzerland
それからこちらはスイスの研究チームです
His analysis is very important
彼の分析は非常に重要です